Welcome to our training on how to set a limit on order handling capacity.
In this video, we'll show you how to set a limit on the number of orders you need to process within
your default handling time.
By using the order handling capacity feature, you can give yourself an extra day to handle any orders
that exceed your set capacity.
This feature helps you manage your order load and protect your account health.
Every offer in the Amazon store comes with a customer delivery promise.
This is the range of dates in which a customer can expect an order to arrive.
Your offers are more attractive when the dates in the customer delivery promise are close to the
time a customer sees your offer.
But if you have more orders than you can handle in a day, it might be difficult to send packages
to customers on time.
Customers need to be able to trust the customer delivery promise since late deliveries affect your
account health.
So how can you achieve a shorter delivery time while also keeping your account health safe?
We have tools to help you do just that.
Let's say you've set a one-day default handling time to help put purchases in the hands of customers
more quickly,
but you're worried about what to do if there's a sudden spike in the number of orders.
Sometimes you can see spikes coming, like around the holiday season.
Other spikes may come out of nowhere, like if your brand suddenly and unexpectedly becomes popular.
Some sellers might worry about getting more orders than they can fulfill, failing to ship within
their handling time and having their account health suffer.
You don't need to extend your default handling time to accommodate potential spikes in ordering.
Instead, you can set your order handling capacity.
Order handling capacity sets a limit on the number of orders you can fulfill within your default
handling time.
If you have a one-day default handling time and the number of orders you get exceeds your order
handling capacity,
Amazon will automatically add a day to the handling time and set all additional orders to a two-
day handling time.
Note that these orders will count toward your next day's limit.
So if your order capacity is 100 orders and you get 120, the extra 20 are put toward the next day's
order capacity.
This way, you'll never have more orders than you can handle and you can protect your account health.
You set your order handling capacity in the same place that you set your default handling time.
Go to the Seller Central home page and open the Settings menu by selecting the gear icon in the
upper right.
Select Shipping Settings and then choose General Shipping Settings on the next screen.
Scroll down until you find handling time.
You will see order handling capacity in the same section where you set your default handling time.
Click Edit to the right.
Look for order handling capacity on the bottom of the next screen.
Here you can input a capacity, then select Save below.
Note that order handling capacity only affects non-prime orders.
If you've set a handling time greater than two days for a specific ASIN, orders for that ASIN will
count toward your daily limit,
but will not have an extra day added when your capacity is reached.
Having an accurate customer delivery promise is an important part of being a successful seller.
Order handling capacity can help you offer a shorter handling time while still protecting your account
health on days when there's a sudden spike in orders.
And that's good news for sellers and customers alike.
This concludes our order handling capacity training.
Thank you and happy selling in the Amazon store.